I want to talk to you today about
sinking in the storm. The feeling that
you get sometimes that you're
overwhelmed.
The feeling that you get sometimes that
there's too much month and not enough
money, too much need and not enough me
to meet it all. That spreadth thin
feeling that that feeling that you get
and it doesn't always announce itself
and all of a sudden there is a storm and
you find yourself sinking in the storm.
Ain't it crazy how you can be singing in
the church and just a few days later
find yourself sinking in the storm?
>> And this place is a place that God has
prepared for us to prepare us for the
storms of our life. You cannot be a
student of Jesus without storms as your
classroom.
>> Anything else would make you arrogant.
Anything else would make you write a
parenting book and your oldest kid is
three.
You're three months pregnant talking
about how to raise teenagers God's way.
What's wrong with you? Go through a
storm and then you'll have something to
say
in this season of your life. God is
calling you to be a student of your
storm.
What does this have to do with thinking?
Well, it's amazing to me how quickly I
can go from stepping on the water, so to
speak, to sinking.
And I can really shift quickly
from being focused on God
to falling down and finding myself in
emotional states that do not resemble
the fruit of the spirit.
>> Okay, just me.
Just me.
>> Look at your neighbor. Say, "It can
happen quick."
>> It can happen quick.
>> It can happen real quick. And if if your
neighbor is looking like they don't know
what I'm talking about, cut them off in
traffic on the way out and see how quick
they go from lifting their hands to
lifting one finger. It can happen. Just
that quick. Can it
>> just get just just even your phone can
buzz in your pocket and it might not
even be the person that you don't want
to hear from with the news that you
don't want to hear. But just the buzz
itself can disrupt your peace, can it?
>> Just even just even the buzz in your
pocket, it can feel like a shot collar
just reminding you that your challenges
are out there in the world. Sometimes it
can happen just that quick. Now, I'm so
glad that Jesus is a savior.
Because I'm a sinner, so I need one.
>> And I have sinful thoughts. All of my
thoughts aren't holy thoughts, good
thoughts, pure thoughts. And so I need
Jesus for my sinful thoughts, which can
become sinful actions, which can become
sinful patterns, which may not send me
to hell, but may make my life on earth
feel like a living hell. Wow.
>> I'm so grateful that Jesus is a savior.
>> And I am also so thankful that he is not
a surface level savior.
>> That he doesn't just save me from hell
when I die, but he saves me from the
hell in my head as he transforms my mind
and brings me through life's challenges.
I need salvation in my soul. That's my
mind, my will, my emotions. I need Jesus
to teach me how to think. And in this
passage that we just read, there's a
conversation between the student of
Jesus and Jesus the Savior.
And Jesus is watching him sink in the
storm. By the way,
you've been feeling like you're sinking
in a storm lately in your life. And it
doesn't have to even be bankruptcy. It
doesn't even have to be something so
catastrophic that everybody would take
up money for you if they knew about it.
It doesn't have to be the worst thing
that ever happened in your life. I just
found that a lot of times I find myself
in like a funk or maybe even a
full-blown feeling of depression. And in
those moments when God is watching me
sink into those states, I'm grateful
that he does not give me surface level
answers like church people do. Cuz
church people will tell you, "Rejoice in
the Lord always."
But they ain't rejoicing in the Lord.
They only been rejoicing in the Lord
because they had a good week.
>> Catch them next week and they might have
a different answer. It can happen that
quick. And Jesus watching Peter fall in
the middle of a storm that had been
raging all night. Remember, he's been
going through this all night. and he
steps out and he's walking and he's
sinking and he cries out, "Lord, save
me." I think that's such an important
phrase. One great theologian who just
went to be with the Lord, Dr. John
MacArthur, used to say, "A lot of us
refuse Jesus as Lord, but we want to use
Jesus as savior."
>> So, I think it's important that he
called him Lord before he called on him
to save him. I'm trying to say that God
wants far more for your life than to
just save you from stupid stuff that you
do.
>> He wants far more for your life than to
just clean up the messes that you make
because you never spend time with him.
>> God wants far more for your life than to
have to redeem years that you waste
because you never get aligned with him.
And so now Peter calls out, "Lord, save
me." And the Bible says immediately
Jesus reached out his hand and caught
him. Now, we focus a lot, and I really
preached this a lot at age 16, how Peter
had the faith to step out when Jesus
said, "Come." Somebody shout, "Come."
>> That's a command. When Jesus gives a
command, you can obey it with
confidence. When Jesus gives a command,
you don't have to start doing the math
on how it's going to work out. When
Jesus gives a command, he already has
the details in mind for how we he will
meet that need before you even know
about the need. So when he says come
take a step
and then we talk so much about the
command that we neglect the question
that I think is just as powerful as the
command. He said come. Peter's coming.
He said walk. Peter's walking. He gave
the word. And Peter is walking not on
water but on one word from Jesus. I
could preach a whole message about
walking on one word. Just one word that
God gives you and you can hang on
through something that you never would
have made it through without that word.
One word from Jesus, the command to
come. But then comes the question after
he caught him. He said, "You of little
faith, why did you doubt?"
Why did you doubt?
Because if I can get beneath the surface
of why you're sinking, I can maybe stop
it from happening so quickly next time.
A lot of times we sink into things and
we don't stop and ask why.
A lot of times we get triggered by
something and after you get triggered,
see, you get trapped
>> and you and you you you don't even
realize how you got triggered until
you're already trapped.
>> I'll break it down for you.
>> I can see we need a little real life
example right now.
>> When Holly and I first got married, we
went on a cruise. I saved up for the
cruise. It was a Princess cruise, which
is a little step up from some of the
other cruises you can buy. I was so
proud of that cruise and so broke after
I paid for it. Three days on the cruise,
she was very quiet one day. And when she
got quiet on that cruise, it triggered
something inside of me that I didn't
know because I equated quiet with bored.
So when she got quiet, I started to get
angry because she was quiet. For Holly,
quiet means relaxed. Quiet means nobody
telling me to do anything. I don't have
to talk. I love you. We're together just
being. This is what she was saying. Your
essence alone
is so captivating.
We don't even need a conversation.
But I interpreted her quiet as boredom.
And we would fight for years in our
marriage. Anytime she would get quiet, I
would think, "You don't like it here?
This isn't good enough for you? Your dad
took you on better vacations? What? You
don't need my vacation? No, I'm
relaxed."
But see, just in such a stupid
illustration like that, you see how
years can go on because I'm reading her
mind with information that is not true
data.
>> And I am triggered by something that
isn't even true. But by the time I
recognize what I'm triggered by, I'm
already trapped in it. And now we're
fighting.
>> And so now it's not that we never get
triggered in our marriage, but here's
what we do. And I I want to teach you
how to do this. We catch it quicker.
>> We catch it quicker.
>> Touch your neighbor, say, "Catch it
quicker."
>> Catch it quicker. Before you blow up on
them, before you go off on them, before
you hit send on the text, proofread it.
Hire yourself as a copy editor and check
that thing one more time. Do you really
want to say you never? Do you really
want to say you always? Do you really
need six exclamation points? Is it
really worth that emoji? Is that emoji
worth the emotional expense of what you
are going to spend the next week
cleaning up? And all of that could have
been cancelled if you would have caught
it quicker and read the text and woke up
in the morning with fresh eyes AND SAID,
"I THINK I'LL JUST HAVE A CONVERSATION."
But we get triggered and then we get
trapped. And that's why the Lord sent a
preacher to you today to give you truth
because the truth can keep you
out of the trap.
>> Preach the word. Larry Stevens Fernick
Jr.
>> I believe I will.
>> So when you start sinking, you get
beneath the surface. And this is what we
need to learn to do. Now they'll tell
you that in therapy. If you go to
therapy, they talk about triggers and
traps and cognitive distortions. And you
sound like you've been in therapy,
Pastor Steve.
No comment.
We need therapy. We also need theology
>> to produce real faith
>> and real change in our life. So, I want
to show you something that I couldn't
end the series without showing you from
Isaiah 55 and overlay it for this
situation that you're facing in your
life. The situation Peter faced where
he's stepping, stepping, stepping, doing
pretty good and then sinking and doesn't
even really understand why. Look at
Isaiah chapter 55.
And I was debating where to start
because the whole passage is so rich.
But for the sake of time, I think I'll
start around verse
6, 7
and start six.
Isaiah 55
verse 6. Yeah, I did on purpose.
verse 6. Now listen to me. This is an
invitation to all of you who have been
sinking in the storm. The Lord offers
you an invitation.
The wind is the trigger
and the sinking is the trap. And
sometimes you feel like you're drowning
in it before you even know what it is.
But this is the word of the Lord and
this will be very rich to you for the
trials that you're going through. The
Lord says, "Seek the Lord while he may
be found. Call on him while he is near."
Let's read that again. Seek the Lord
while he may be found. Call on him while
he is near. I'm coming back to that.
Call on him while he's near. Let the
wicked forsake their ways and the
unrighteous their thoughts.
So, this is interesting language. I I'll
read the whole passage, but that's where
I want to camp out around verse six or
seven.
Let the wicked forsake their ways and
the unrighteous their thoughts. Let them
turn to the Lord, and he will have mercy
on them and to our God, for he will
freely pardon. For my thoughts are not
your thoughts,
>> neither are my ways
>> your ways, declares the Lord.
>> As the heavens are higher
higher than the earth,
>> so my ways are higher than your ways.
God says, I know how to do my job.
>> God says, I know who to let leave you.
God says, "I know who to bring into your
life." That is a challenge for you.
>> You keep praying to be a masterpiece and
every time I send someone to be the
sandpaper, you push them away. But I
know what tools to use to turn you into
the disciple that I want you to be. He
says, "My ways are higher than your ways
and my thoughts than your thoughts. as
the rain and the snow come down from
heaven and do not return to it without
watering the earth and making it bud and
flourish so that it yields seed for the
sewer and bread for the eater. So is my
word that goes out from my mouth.
>> I hear Jesus saying come. When I read
Isaiah 55, I I feel the echo of this
prophecy in Matthew chapter 14. I feel
the power of one word from God. He says
so is my word. Just one word. So is my
word. The full counsel of the word of
God has value. But just one singular
word that goes from my mouth. It will
not return to me empty, but will
accomplish what I desire and achieve the
purpose. Many are the plans, but it is
the purpose for which I sent it that
will be accomplished. So why did Jesus
send a disciple into a storm that he
knew was going to happen? And why does
God allow challenges to our faith
instead of just bolstering us with the
Bible so that we avoid them? And Isaiah
55 gives an interesting strategy. Okay,
let me teach you what Isaiah is teaching
here. He says, "You can seek the Lord,
you can call on him, but you have to be
willing, verse 7, to forsake your ways
and your unrighteous thoughts." Now,
that's interesting language
to say that I'm going to forsake a
thought. That's crazy to me because when
you say forsake something, it's
something that you have become very
attached to.
>> You don't forsake something that you
don't even know.
>> You don't even know it. To forsake
something is to walk away from something
that it is assumed you have
responsibility for. So when God says, "I
will never leave you nor forsake you,"
forsaking has baked into it the idea
that I am responsible for this. I'm not
saying it right. How say it?
>> You can drop a thought.
>> Like this notebook, just notebook. You
can drop a thought. He said, "Forsake
>> your ways
>> cuz my ways are higher." Yeah.
>> And your thoughts that are not from God.
>> And how many times have I been drowning
in my mind and in my life
because of the thought that I wouldn't
drop
>> about my situation?
How many times have I clung to an
offense?
>> Wow.
>> While I'm drowning
in my bitterness
>> and I am asking God to help me forgive.
>> But if I don't drop, let me do it again.
If I don't drop the thought,
>> I drown.
>> That's what I'm trying to say. Now I
said it the way I want to say it. Tell
your neighbor, "Drop it or drown."
That's the only two options you have
right now because you can't afford to
play around with this right now because
there's too much at stake at this
juncture of your life right now. It's
drop it or drown. You've got to stop
thinking childishly about this and
waiting on people to come around and
make it right. And you just got to get
your heart right with God. And you've
got to let him show you what he's going
to do from the place that you're at, not
the place that you wanted to be.
Punch your neighbor. Say, "Drop it. Drop
it so you don't drown. Drop it so you
don't keep sinking. Drop it so it
doesn't weigh you down. Drop it so you
don't miss the last the next season that
God wants to give you. Crying about the
season that you lost. You better drop
this thing." And and and the thing about
dropping a thought is it's kind of hard
for me to drop my thought
>> until I understand that God
>> can also drop a thought.
>> This is one thing I'm ready to preach
today. This is one thing that me and God
have in common. We can both drop
thoughts. I can take a thought in my
mind. I can take a tempting thought. I
can take a a a bitter thought. I can
take an angry thought. I can take a
victimized thought. I can take a
catastrophizing thought. I can take a
wicked thought. I can take a thought and
I can look at it and I can separate
myself from the thought. And by the
grace of Jesus, by the grace of God, by
the power of the Holy Spirit, I can look
at the thought and realize that just
because I think it doesn't mean I have
to be it.
>> So, I can drop a thought.
How dumb would it be for you to drown on
this sea because of something you won't
drop? HOW DUMB WOULD IT BE? THE BIBLE
SAYS, "FORSAKE YOUR thoughts when
they're not God's ways." His ways are
higher. So when he shows you the higher
way, don't stay down in the way you did
it, the way they did it, the way you
thought you were going to do it. Drop
your thoughts so God can drop his.
>> What you mean God can drop a thought?
I mean like airdrop.
>> I mean like how I could take my phone
and put it next to your phone
>> and if it's near enough,
>> you can choose to share with me what's
on your phone,
>> on my phone. Right?
>> If we are close enough
>> to connect,
>> you can drop something to me
>> that I didn't come with.
>> And now you know why it was important
for you to be at church today
>> so you could get close to God and close
to somebody. Fist bump your neighbor and
say, "I'll drop you some faith today."
>> Fist bump them real quick and say, "I
got something for you. I got something
for you." Tell them, "I'll airrop you
some peace today. I'll air drop you some
joy today." The Bible says that if two
of you will agree, well, we got a lot
more than two, baby boy. And the Holy
Ghost in me is the Holy Ghost in you.
And if you came a little empty today,
there is a word from God. And if you
don't feel it right now, then praise him
by faith till something clicks in your
spirit and you'll get the sense. I think
I'm going to be all right.
High five your neighbor like you're air
dropping something.
Oh, that's good, isn't it? Isn't that
good to know that God can drop you a
thought? Forget about a human. THEY
MIGHT NOT HAVE IT. BUT IF I'M CLOSE
ENOUGH TO JESUS, WHAT I DIDN'T GET FROM
OTHER PEOPLE, WHAT I DIDN'T HAVE IN MY
FLESH, GOD DID BY SENDING his son. See,
so
you can drop a thought
>> and so can God. And the moment you drop
your low thought, the moment you drop
your human thought, the moment you drop
your thinking thought, notice the Bible
says that immediately
>> Jesus reached out his hand and caught
him.
>> Yeah.
>> Hey, thanks for stopping by my YouTube
channel. I hope you were blessed today.
If you were, share this with somebody.
Like and subscribe and leave me a
comment. Let me know where you're
watching from, what we can pray for you
about. Hope to see you back here again
really soon.